# **ALFRED BOATENG**

Kumasi, Ghana 233 • +233541034798 • kwadwo.boateng.alfred@gmail.com

### Websites, Portfolios, Profiles

- https://www.linkedin.com/in/learnwithalfred
- https://alfredboateng.netlify.app/
- https://github.com/learnwithalfred
- https://www.youtube.com/@learnwithalfred
- https://medium.com/@learnwithalfred

### **Professional Summary**

Well-qualified Full Stack Developer familiar with wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements. Handles any part of process with ease. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities offering 3 years of related experience.

### **Skills**

- JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Redux, jQuery, PHP, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Node.js, Laravel, MongoDB, Express Js, React, Angular, Next.JS, Remix, Redux (incl. Redux Saga), Styled Components, Emotion, RTK Query, Firebase, Material UI, Tailwind CSS, CSS
- Databases: Oracle, SQL Server, MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL
- Tools & Methods: Git, Azure DevOps, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile, RSpec, TDD

- Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring, Project
  Management, Quality Assurance
- Application development, Database Programming, Code reviews

### **Work History**

Full Stack Developer, 01/2023 to Current

Juubix - Remote

- Coordinated deployments of new software, feature updates, and fixes.
- Supervised work of programmers, designers, and technicians, assigned tasks, and monitoring performance against targets.
- Analyzed existing software implementations to identify areas requiring improvement.
- Managed over 10 developers per day.
- Contributed ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines, designs, and enhancements.
- Conducted data modeling, performance, and integration testing.
- Tested and deployed scalable and highly available software products.
- Worked with back-end developers to design APIs

#### Full Stack Web Developer, 09/2022 to 01/2023

#### **TobeDetermend** – Remote, Canada

- Worked with back-end developers to design APIs.
- Developed and maintained microservices architectures using Docker, Kubernetes, and OpenShift.
- Used Node.JS, ORM, and SQL/No-SQL to develop and manage databases.
- Boosted network, system, and data availability and integrity through preventive maintenance and upgrades.
- Designed testing protocols to locate issues within the system.
- Used Javascript, SQL, and HTML to develop app solutions.
- Collaborated with fellow engineers to evaluate software and hardware interfaces.
- Increased sales by 10%

#### Freelance Web Developer, 01/2020 to 09/2022

#### Self Employed – Accra, Ghana

- Developed technical solutions required to accommodate specific user-facing assets
- Pulled from PHP, SQL, JavaScript, and other back-end library knowledge to bolster programming resources.
- Provided security maintenance and patching on website interface to maintain viability after launch.
- Implemented Google-based SEO and ad campaigns to meet budget specifications.
- Coded websites using Angular.js, Raect.js, PHP, Laravel, Python, Django, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and jQuery languages.
- Adhered to SEO best practices while designing sites.
- Multi-tasked across multiple functions and roles to meet deadlines and organizational expectations.
- Engaged with clients to plan and optimize site issues and queries.
- Discussed site and app requirements with clients to produce actionable development plans.
- Managed over 20 customer calls per day.
- Applied emerging technologies to update and maintain site applicability.
- Projects completed includes christmodel.academy and aurageospatial.com

#### Full Stack Developer Intern, 06/2021 to 01/2022

#### Kraado - Accra, Ghana

- Worked with senior developers and designers to implement Software using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React.
- Boosted web traffic by improving navigation and rectifying bottlenecks.
- Cultivated good working relationships with clients, strategic partners and internal teams and explained technical concepts clearly to internal and external audiences.
- Conceived and built optimized landing pages in HTML and CSS for integration and crossbrowser compatibility.
- Completed full redesigns of existing websites to improve navigation, enhance visuals and strengthen search engine rankings.
- Increased sales by 10%.
- Crafted SEO strategy and intuitive interface for site to achieve prominent rankings across top browser platforms

- Employed coding practices based on commonly accepted standards to establish site layout and user interface
- Monitored technical performance of internal systems and gathered information from consumers about program functionality
- Collaborated with in-house web designers to create sleek and innovative UI design
- Developed, coded, modified and debugged application programs of varying degree of complexity with full independence
- Helped code and test software based web application software based on Agile Scrum and Kanban approaches
- Developed user-friendly web forms with validation and error handling

### **Education**

Certificate in Web Development: Web Development, 01/2023

Microverse - United States, Remote

High School Diploma: 08/2013

KNUST - Kumasi, Ghana

## **Accomplishments**

- Presented team accomplishments and provided valuable feedback to experimenters, resulting in improved team performance
- Learn to work with a new framework (Sinatra) and contributed to creating video streaming app with it

## Languages

#### **English**

Upper intermediate (B2)